NIKESH E

Male | Indian | 24 years

+919176802905 | nikesh5050@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikesh5050

I am a passionate engineer looking forward to work in a challenging and fast-paced environment.

EDUCATION

B.Tech 2012-2016 Electrical and Electronics Engineering 8.59 (CGPA)

(National Institute of Technology, Tiruchirappalli)

Class XII (CBSE) 2012 School Name: Chettinad Vidyashram, Chennai 96.8% Class X (CBSE) 2010 School Name: Chettinad Vidyashram, Chennai 9.4 GPA

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS AND CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Won first prize and **Chandrasekar gopalan award** in 'SANGAM' event for displaying project on 'KEKULE-SNAKE BOT' during 'PRAGYAN 2014', the international technomanagement festival of NIT Trichy. The bot was developed using dynamixel servos with Atmega 328 AVR Microcontroller.
- Conducted hands-on workshop for freshman students with RMI-NITT Wall follower (2013). Content taught: Basic Mechanics and electronics, Line Sensor Circuits, peripherals of Atmega 16, bot fabrication.
- Won **2**nd **position** in Zonal rounds of Robo Tryst-2013, a National Level Robotics Championship, organized by Robosapiens Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
- Conducted workshop during Currents'15 on Mobi-Robotics: Manual Robot control using DTMF and Accelerometer using MSP430 Microcontroller.

SKILL SET

• Languages : C,C++

• Operating System: Windows, Linux

Packages : Eclipse, Keil, Arduino, Pspice, MATLAB, MS Project, MS office

• Certification : Mastering Microcontroller with Embedded Driver Development(Udemy)

• Hands on experience with boards: Arduino, CC3200,MSP430,STM32Nucleo,ESP8266,ESP32

CAREER OVERVIEW

• Subject Matter Expert, Chegg Inc. (Part-Time)(April 2019 -present)

Online tutor in the field of Electrical & Electronics, provide solutions/answers for subject specific problems/questions posted on the website (www.chegg.com).

• Senior engineer, Larsen & Toubro Construction (Bellary, Karnataka) (2017 – July 2018)

Planning In-charge, responsible for billing & documentation, mobilization of resources, planning of activities, coordinating with people of other disciplines in Transmission Line Business Unit.

PROJECT WORK/ TRAINING

Automated power management system

(2015-2016)

Under Dr. S. Moorthi, Assistant Professor, EEE, NIT Trichy.

The project focuses on Distribution-side management system (DMS) that aims to effectively operate integrated power management systems.

Sensors input data to a system which collects data and analyses the data which in turn controls the supply from various sources to give the most economical operation.

The consumer can also monitor the power consumption pattern using the designed web interface on the go through any mobile which has access to internet. (CC3200 ARM based microcontroller)

• Intelligent WSN system for smart-induced green building

(2015 - 2016)

Under Dr. S. Moorthi, Assistant Professor, EEE, NIT Trichy.

Developing an intelligent WSN system composed of several nodes that collects electrical parameters like current, voltage & sensor data like temperature, motion and controls the node. (CC3200 ARM based microcontroller)

"KEKULE-SNAKE BOT"

(2013-2014)

Under RMI (robotics and machine intelligence) club of NIT Trichy.

Developed a snake bot that can perform 6 different types of reptilian motions. This can be used in industrial, search & rescue, military stealth surveillance applications. This has also won the 1st prize & Chandrasekar gopalan award during **PRAGYAN 2014,** International Techno-management festival of NIT Trichy (Atmega 328).

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Positions of Responsibility:

- **Deputy Manager for workshops** at CURRENTS' 15, The National Level Technical Symposium of Electrical and Electronics Engineering Department, National Institute of Technology, Trichy.
- **Inventory coordinator, Member** of RMI 'Robotics and Machine Intelligence' club of National Institute of Technology, Trichy.

Others:

- Part of **NSS** team of NIT Trichy which organized events for school children from nearby localities. Volunteered in planning and scheduling the events.
- Participated in the **FIRST TECH CHALLENGE** (FTC) conducted by caterpillar during March 2015.
- Displayed project on "PARALLEL MANIPULATORS" a 3 DOF platform actuated by three dynamixels, during 'PRAGYAN 2015' International Techno-management festival of NIT Trichy.
- Recipient of the 'Scholarship for Higher Education' conferred by the Department of Science and Technology, Govt. of India under the INSPIRE Scheme for ranking within the top 1% in the CBSE class XII examination, 2012.
- Hobbies include playing table tennis, origami, and video games, solving sodoku.